Guide to the Preliminary Guide to the Marc H. Ratzlaff Veterinary Medicine Films 1976-1990
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Preliminary Guide to the Marc H. Ratzlaff Veterinary Medicine Films
1976-1990
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
MS 2019.13
Ratzlaff, Marc H.
6.25 Linear feet of shelf space 7 Boxes
This collection consists of 16mm films of veterinary surgical procedures, mostly on horses and dogs, including Triple Crown winner Seattle Slew. It also contains logs with procedures performed and associated film roll numbers.
Marc H. Ratzlaff is a professor emeritus in the Department of Veterinary and Comparative Anatomy, Pharmacology and Physiology (VCAPP) at Washington State University (WSU).
This collection consists of 16mm films of veterinary surgical procedures, mostly on horses and dogs, including Triple Crown winner Seattle Slew. It also contains logs with procedures performed and associated film roll numbers.
This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records’ creator or preliminary sorting performed by staff.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Charlie Powell at the WSU School of Veterinary Medicine donated this collection to the Washington State University Libraries in 2019 (MS.2019.13).
The repository expects to receive additions to this collection.
Washington State University College of Veterinary Medicine Records, 1932-1975 (Archives 21)
Washington State University College of Veterinary Medicine Records, 1957-1973 (Archives 53)
Washington State University College of Veterinary Medicine Records, 1976-1978 (Archives 173)
Washington State University College of Veterinary Medicine Associate Dean Records, 1976-1978 (Archives 177)
Washington State University College of Veterinary Medicine Records, 1976-1982 (Archives 379)
Washington State University Veterinary Clinical Medicine and Surgery Narcotics Register, 1957-1968 (Cage 4013)
Smithcors Collection of Veterinary History Documents, 1851-1996 (Cage 693)
Earl Edward Wegner Veterinary Medicine Photographs and Scrapbooks, 1905-1947 (PC 8)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Ratzlaff, Marc H. -- Archives
Washington State University. College of Veterinary Medicine -- Records and correspondence
Veterinary surgery -- Washington (State) -- History; Veterinary medicine -- Washington (State) -- History
Agriculture; Washington (State); Colleges and Universities; Moving Images
- Film inventory, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Edited film log – films are categorized by disorder, such as Neurological Disorders, Rear Leg Problems, Canine- Miscellaneous, Wobblers, and Carpal Lameness, among others, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Film log: Bolex and Locam, 1979 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Film log: Photosonics ActionMaster, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Single sheet film inventory- includes Seattle Slew; inconsistent with information – name and procedure not always given, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Film log: storage, 1979 December (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Notebook: film logs, requests for cinematography, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 16mm films, many unlabeled, Circa 1970s-1990 (Box 2)
- 16mm films, many unlabeled, Circa 1970s-1990 (Box 3)
- 16mm films, many unlabeled, Circa 1970s-1990 (Box 4)
- 16mm films, many unlabeled, Circa 1970s-1990 (Box 5)
- 16mm films, many unlabeled, Circa 1970s-1990 (Box 6)
- 16mm films, many unlabeled, Circa 1970s-1990 (Box 7)